<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<metadata>
	<idinfo>
	<citation>
			<citeinfo>
				<origin>AtkinsRealis</origin>
				<pubdate>20240514</pubdate>
				<title>Data Capture Hydraulics  - BLE AREA 1A, IA FY20/21 DISC-BLE</title>
				<edition>Version 2.8.5.6</edition>
                <geoform>FEMA-DCS-Hydraulics</geoform>
      <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Washington, DC</pubplace>
        <publish>Federal Emergency Management Agency</publish>
        </pubinfo>
      <onlink>https://msc.fema.gov</onlink>
      <lworkcit>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Federal Emergency Management Agency</origin>
          <pubdate>20240830</pubdate>
          <title>FEMA CASE 21-07-0002S</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </lworkcit>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
		<descript>
			<abstract>Recent developments in digital terrain and geospatial database management technology make it possible to protect this
				investment for existing and future projects to a much greater extent than was possible in the past. The minimum requirement
				for hydraulics data includes input and output files for all hydraulic models and spatial datasets that are needed to implement
				the models.(Source: FEMA Guidelines and Standards for Flood Risk Analysis and Mapping.)</abstract>
			<purpose>Development of a Base Level Engineering (BLE) 2D hydraulic model to provide water-surface elevations and to characterize
				both pluvial and fluvial hazards contributing to increasing coverage of more comprehensive and graduated hazard
				identification products.</purpose>
		</descript>
		<timeperd>
			<timeinfo>
				<sngdate>
					<caldate>20240830</caldate>
				</sngdate>
			</timeinfo>
			<current>MIP Submission Date</current>
		</timeperd>
		<status>
			<progress>In work</progress>
			<update>Unknown</update>
		</status>
        <spdom>
      		<bounding>
				<westbc>-90.851</westbc>
				<eastbc>-89.704</eastbc>
				<northbc>42.757</northbc>
				<southbc>41.874</southbc>
      		</bounding>
        </spdom>
		<keywords>
			<theme>
				<themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
				<themekey>environment</themekey>
				<themekey>inlandWaters</themekey>
			</theme>
			<theme>
				<themekt>FEMA NFIP Topic Category</themekt>
				<themekey>Hydraulics</themekey>
				<themekey>Flood Insurance Rate Map</themekey>
				<themekey>FIRM</themekey>
				<themekey>Flood Hazard Data</themekey>
				<themekey>0.2-Percent-Annual-Chance Flood</themekey>
				<themekey>1-Percent-Annual-Chance Flood</themekey>
				<themekey>2-Percent-Annual-Chance Flood</themekey>
				<themekey>4-Percent-Annual-Chance Flood</themekey>
				<themekey>10-Percent-Annual-Chance Flood</themekey>
				<themekey>1-Percent-Plus-Annual-Chance Flood</themekey>
				<themekey>Stream</themekey>
				<themekey>Lake</themekey>
				<themekey>Water Body</themekey>
				<themekey>Base Flood Elevation</themekey>
				<themekey>2D Model</themekey>
				<themekey>Fluvial Flood</themekey>
				<themekey>Pluvial Flood</themekey>
				<themekey>Profile Baseline</themekey>
				<themekey>Backwater</themekey>
				<themekey>BFE</themekey>
				<themekey>Flood Profile</themekey>
				<themekey>Bridge</themekey>
				<themekey>Culvert</themekey>
				<themekey>Manning's Roughness Coefficient (Manning's n)</themekey>
			</theme>
			<place>
				<placekt>None</placekt>
				<placekey>REGION 07</placekey>
				<placekey>STATE IA</placekey>
				<placekey>FEMA-CID AP20IA</placekey>
				<placekey>COUNTY DUBUQUE</placekey>
				<placekey>COUNTY-FIPS 19061</placekey>
				<placekey>COUNTY CLINTON</placekey>
				<placekey>COUNTY-FIPS 19045</placekey>
				<placekey>COUNTY JACKSON</placekey>
				<placekey>COUNTY-FIPS 19097</placekey>
				<placekey>COMMUNITY ANDOVER, CITY OF</placekey>
				<placekey>COMMUNITY CLINTON, CITY OF</placekey>
				<placekey>CLINTON COUNTY UNINCORPORATED AREAS</placekey>
				<placekey>COMMUNITY ASBURY, CITY OF</placekey>
				<placekey>COMMUNITY PEOSTA, CITY OF</placekey>
				<placekey>COMMUNITY CENTRALIA, CITY OF</placekey>
				<placekey>DUBUQUE COUNTY UNINCORPORATED AREAS</placekey>
				<placekey>COMMUNITY DUBUQUE, CITY OF</placekey>
				<placekey>COMMUNITY SPRINGBROOK, CITY OF</placekey>
				<placekey>COMMUNITY ST. DONATUS, CITY OF</placekey>
				<placekey>COMMUNITY BELLEVUE, CITY OF</placekey>
				<placekey>COMMUNITY SABULA, CITY OF</placekey>
				<placekey>COMMUNITY MILES, CITY OF</placekey>
				<placekey>JACKSON COUNTY UNINCORPORATED AREAS</placekey>
				<placekey>FEMA-CID 190034</placekey>
				<placekey>FEMA-CID 190088</placekey>
				<placekey>FEMA-CID 190859</placekey>
				<placekey>FEMA-CID 190053</placekey>
				<placekey>FEMA-CID 190079</placekey>
				<placekey>FEMA-CID 190500</placekey>
				<placekey>FEMA-CID 190534</placekey>
				<placekey>FEMA-CID 195180</placekey>
				<placekey>FEMA-CID 190047</placekey>
				<placekey>FEMA-CID 190106</placekey>
				<placekey>FEMA-CID 190158</placekey>
				<placekey>FEMA-CID 190162</placekey>
				<placekey>FEMA-CID 190779</placekey>
				<placekey>FEMA-CID 190879</placekey>
			</place>
	</keywords>
	<accconst>None</accconst>
	<useconst>Acknowledgement of FEMA would be appreciated in products derived from these data.  These digital data are produced for the purposes of updating/creating a FIRM Database.</useconst>
	<native>The hydraulic modeling was performed using HECRAS 6.2 and HECRAS 6.3.1. The raster data were created in RASMAPPER environment.</native>
	</idinfo>
	<dataqual>
		<attracc>
			<attraccr>The FIRM Database consists of vector files and associated attributes produced in conjunction with the hardcopy FEMA FIRM.
				The published effective FIRM and FIRM Database are issued as the official designation of the SFHAs. As such they are adopted by
				local communities and form the basis for administration of the NFIP. For these purposes they are authoritative.
				Provisions exist in the regulations for public review, appeals and corrections of the flood risk information shown
				to better match real world conditions. As with any engineering analysis of this type, variation from the estimated
				flood heights and floodplain boundaries is possible. Details of FEMA's requirements for the FISs and flood mapping
				process that produces these data are available in the Guidelines and Standards for Flood Risk Analysis and Mapping.
				Attribute accuracy was tested by manual comparison of source graphics with hardcopy plots and a symbolized display
				on an interactive computer graphic system.
Independent quality control testing of the FIRM Database was also performed.</attraccr>
		</attracc>
		<logic>Hydraulic analysis uses all valid existing flood elevation, survey, hydrologic analysis results, and other
			pertinent information for the study area. FEMA approved models are used to compute water surface elevations for required flood events.
			Computed water surface elevations and topographic data are used to delineate flood hazard boundaries. Roughness coefficients are
			carefully selected to represent the conditions along stream beds and banks. Hydraulics Data Capture submittals match the model
			output with respect to floodplain boundaries, cross sections, and water surface elevations and their precision.  Floodplain boundaries
			and cross sections are not cartographically modified, and the data may not necessarily agree exactly with the published regulatory FIRM,
			FIRM Database, flood profiles, and Floodway Data Tables.</logic>
		<complete>Hydraulic analysis provides water surface elevations at different locations along the stream and for
			different flooding events. Hydraulic submittal includes key physical data used in the process, model parameters and model
			output. Data developed in surveying and hydrologic analysis are incorporated in hydraulic analysis. Results of hydraulic
			analysis are used to map Special Flood Hazard Area (SFHA) boundaries. Selection of model parameters (e.g., roughness
			coefficients, expansion and contraction coefficients, etc) is supported by additional information (e.g., landuse, aerial photo, etc).
			Model boundary conditions are carefully selected and justified. Modeled velocities are checked for potential erosion.</complete>
		<posacc>
			<horizpa>
				<horizpar>The FIRM Database consists of vector files and associated attributes produced in conjunction with the hardcopy FEMA
					FIRM. The published effective FIRM and FIRM Database are issued as the official designation of the SFHAs. As such they are
					adopted by local communities and form the basis for administration of the NFIP. For these purposes they are authoritative.
					Provisions exist in the regulations for public review, appeals and corrections of the flood risk information shown to better
					match real world conditions. As with any engineering analysis of this type, variation from the estimated flood heights and
					floodplain boundaries is possible. Details of FEMA's requirements for the FIS and flood mapping process that produces these
					data are available in the Guidelines and Standards for Flood Risk Analysis and Mapping. Horizontal accuracy was tested by
					manual comparison of source graphics with hardcopy plots and a symbolized display on an interactive computer graphic system.
					Independent quality control testing of the FIRM Database was also performed.</horizpar>
			</horizpa>
			<vertacc>
				<vertaccr>The FIRM Database consists of vector files and associated attributes produced in conjunction
					with the hardcopy FEMA FIRM. The published effective FIRM and FIRM Database are issued as the official
					designation of the SFHAs. As such they are adopted by local communities and form the basis for
					administration of the NFIP. For these purposes they are authoritative. Provisions exist in the
					regulations for public review, appeals and corrections of the flood risk information shown to
					better match real world conditions. As with any engineering analysis of this type, variation
					from the estimated flood heights and floodplain boundaries is possible. Details of FEMA's
					requirements for the FISs and flood mapping process that produces these data are available in
					the Guidelines and Standards for Flood Risk Analysis and Mapping. Vertical accuracy was tested
					by manual comparison of source graphics with hardcopy plots and a symbolized display on an interactive computer graphic system.
Independent quality control testing of the FIRM database was also performed.</vertaccr>
			</vertacc>
		</posacc>
        <lineage>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                  <citeinfo>
                    <origin>AtkinsRealis</origin>
                  <pubdate>20240830</pubdate>
                  <title>Iowa Statewide 2D BLE - Area 1A</title>
                  <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
                  <pubinfo>
                      <pubplace>Calverton, MD</pubplace>
                    <publish>AtkinsRealis</publish>
                    </pubinfo>
                  <othercit>Effective FIS and FIRM for , </othercit>
                  </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
              <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
              <typesrc>Digital</typesrc>
              <srctime>
                  <timeinfo>
                    <sngdate>
                      <caldate>20240830</caldate>
                    </sngdate>
                  </timeinfo>
                <srccurr>Publication date</srccurr>
                </srctime>
              <srccitea>STUDY14</srccitea>
              <srccontr>S_BFE, S_FLD_HAZ_AR, S_FLD_HAZ_LN, S_Hydro_Reach, S_Nodes, S_PROFIL_BASLN, S_Subbasins, S_Submittal_Info</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>The FIRM Database is compiled in conjunction with the hardcopy FIRM and the final FIS report.
                    The specifics of the hydrologic and hydraulic analyses performed are detailed in the FIS report. The
                    results of these studies are submitted in digital format to FEMA. These data and unrevised data from
                    effective FIRMs are compiled onto the base map used for FIRM publication and checked for accuracy
                    and compliance with FEMA standards.
                </procdesc>
                <procdate>20240830</procdate>
            </procstep>
        </lineage>
	</dataqual>
	<spref>
		<horizsys>
			<planar>
				<gridsys>
					<gridsysn>State Plane Coordinate System 1983</gridsysn>
					<spcs>
						<spcszone>3417</spcszone>
						<transmer>
							<sfctrmer>0.3048006096012192</sfctrmer>
<!--							# 1 meter = 3.280833333333333 feet-->
							<longcm>-93.5</longcm>
							<latprjo>41.5</latprjo>
							<feast>4921250.0</feast>
							<fnorth>3280833.33</fnorth>
						</transmer>
					</spcs>
				</gridsys>
				<planci>
					<plance>coordinate pair</plance>
					<coordrep>
						<absres>0.004096</absres>
						<ordres>0.004096</ordres>
					</coordrep>
					<plandu>US Feet</plandu>
				</planci>
			</planar>
			<geodetic>
				<horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
				<ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
				<semiaxis>6378137</semiaxis>
				<denflat>298.2572</denflat>
			</geodetic>
		</horizsys>
	</spref>
	<eainfo>
		<detailed>
			<enttyp>
				<enttypl>S_Hydro_Reach</enttypl>
				<enttypd>Location and attributes for lines that represent the connectivity between the subbasins and flow direction between nodes within the study area. </enttypd>
				<enttypds>FEMA FIRM Database Technical Reference (available at http://www.fema.gov/guidelines-and-standards-flood-risk-analysis-and-mapping and on the FEMA Risk MAP Knowledge Sharing Site).</enttypds>
			</enttyp>
		</detailed>
		<detailed>
			<enttyp>
				<enttypl>S_Fld_Haz_Ar</enttypl>
				<enttypd>A spatial data set consisting of polygons that represent the extent of the flood zones.</enttypd>
				<enttypds>FEMA FIRM Database Technical Reference (available at http://www.fema.gov/guidelines-and-standards-flood-risk-analysis-and-mapping and on the FEMA Risk MAP Knowledge Sharing Site).</enttypds>
			</enttyp>
		</detailed>
		<detailed>
			<enttyp>
				<enttypl>S_Gen_Struct</enttypl>
				<enttypd>A spatial data set consisting of lines that depict the location of structures.</enttypd>
				<enttypds>FEMA FIRM Database Technical Reference (available at http://www.fema.gov/guidelines-and-standards-flood-risk-analysis-and-mapping and on the FEMA Risk MAP Knowledge Sharing Site).</enttypds>
			</enttyp>
		</detailed>
		<detailed>
			<enttyp>
				<enttypl>S_Nodes</enttypl>
				<enttypd>A spatial dataset consisting of points that represent sub basin outlets, juctions, reservoirs, structures or diversions.</enttypd>
				<enttypds>FEMA FIRM Database Technical Reference (available at http://www.fema.gov/guidelines-and-standards-flood-risk-analysis-and-mapping and on the FEMA Risk MAP Knowledge Sharing Site).</enttypds>
			</enttyp>
		</detailed>
		<detailed>
			<enttyp>
				<enttypl>S_Levee</enttypl>
				<enttypd>A spatial dataset consisting of lines that represent the centerlines of levees.</enttypd>
				<enttypds>FEMA FIRM Database Technical Reference (available at http://www.fema.gov/guidelines-and-standards-flood-risk-analysis-and-mapping and on the FEMA Risk MAP Knowledge Sharing Site).</enttypds>
			</enttyp>
		</detailed>
		<detailed>
			<enttyp>
				<enttypl>S_Profil_BasLn</enttypl>
				<enttypd>A spatial data set consisting of lines showing the flow path used for floodplain modeling and mapping.</enttypd>
				<enttypds>FEMA FIRM Database Technical Reference (available at http://www.fema.gov/guidelines-and-standards-flood-risk-analysis-and-mapping and on the FEMA Risk MAP Knowledge Sharing Site).</enttypds>
			</enttyp>
		</detailed>
		<detailed>
			<enttyp>
				<enttypl>S_Subbasins</enttypl>
				<enttypd>A spatial dataset consisting of polygons representing watershed or subwatershed areas contributing runoff to the discharge points used in the hydrologic analysis. </enttypd>
				<enttypds>FEMA FIRM Database Technical Reference (available at http://www.fema.gov/guidelines-and-standards-flood-risk-analysis-and-mapping and on the FEMA Risk MAP Knowledge Sharing Site).</enttypds>
			</enttyp>
		</detailed>
		<detailed>
			<enttyp>
				<enttypl>S_Submittal_Info</enttypl>
				<enttypd>A spatial data set consisting of polygons depicting the extents of the studied area.</enttypd>
				<enttypds>FEMA FIRM Database Technical Reference (available at http://www.fema.gov/guidelines-and-standards-flood-risk-analysis-and-mapping and on the FEMA Risk MAP Knowledge Sharing Site).</enttypds>
			</enttyp>
		</detailed>
		<overview>
			<eaover>The Hydraulic submittal is made up of several data themes containing both spatial and attribute information. These data represent the extent of flooding and the water surface elevations for the subject area. The spatial data files and attribute tables include profile flood hazard boundaries and other data related to the NFIP.</eaover>
			<eadetcit>FEMA's FIRM Database Technical Reference contains a detailed description of each attribute code and a reference to other relevant information.</eadetcit>
		</overview>
	</eainfo>
	<distinfo>
		<distrib>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntorgp>
					<cntorg>FEMA, Mapping Information Platform</cntorg>
				</cntorgp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing</addrtype>
					<address>500 C Street, S.W.</address>
					<city>Washington</city>
					<state>District of Columbia</state>
					<postal>20472</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>1-877-336-2627</cntvoice>
				<cntemail>miphelp@riskmapcds.com</cntemail>
			</cntinfo>
		</distrib>
		<distliab>No warranty expressed or implied is made by FEMA regarding the utility of the data on any other system nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty.</distliab>
		<stdorder>
			<digform>
				<digtinfo>
					<formname>FEMA-DCS-Hydraulics</formname>
				</digtinfo>
				<digtopt>
					<onlinopt>
						<computer>
							<networka>
								<networkr>http://hazards.fema.gov</networkr>
							</networka>
						</computer>
					</onlinopt>
				</digtopt>
			</digform>
			<fees>Contact Distributor</fees>
		</stdorder>
	</distinfo>
	<metainfo>
		<metd>20240830</metd>
		<metc>
			<cntinfo>
				<cntperp>
					<cntper>MIPHelp</cntper>
					<cntorg>Federal Emergency Management Agency</cntorg>
				</cntperp>
				<cntaddr>
					<addrtype>mailing</addrtype>
					<address>500 C Street, S.W.</address>
					<city>Washington</city>
					<state>District of Columbia</state>
					<postal>20472</postal>
					<country>USA</country>
				</cntaddr>
				<cntvoice>1-877-336-2627</cntvoice>
				<cntemail>miphelp@riskmapcds.com</cntemail>
			</cntinfo>
		</metc>
		<metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
		<metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
		<metextns>
			<onlink>http://hazards.fema.gov</onlink>
			<onlink>http://www.epsg.org</onlink>
			<metprof>FEMA NFIP Metadata Content and Format Standard</metprof>
		</metextns>
	</metainfo>
</metadata>
