<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<metadata>
  <idinfo>
    <citation>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>AtkinsRealis</origin>
        <pubdate>20240930</pubdate>
        <title>BLE Area 3 MO-Little Sioux, Iowa FY22 DISC-BLE</title>
        <edition>2.8.5.6</edition>
        <geoform>FEMA-DCS-Hydraulics</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Washington, DC</pubplace>
          <publish>Federal Emergency Management Agency</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>https://hazards.fema.gov</onlink>
        <lworkcit>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>Federal Emergency Management Agency</origin>
            <pubdate>20240930</pubdate>
            <title>FEMA CASE 23-07-0037S</title>
          </citeinfo>
        </lworkcit>
      </citeinfo>
    </citation>
    <descript>
      <abstract>Recent developments in digital terrain and geospatial database management technology make it possible to protect this investment for existing and future projects to a much greater extent than was possible in the past. The minimum requirement for hydraulics data includes input and output files for all hydraulic models and spatial datasets that are needed to implement the models.(Source: FEMA Guidelines and Standards for Flood Risk Analysis and Mapping.)</abstract>
      <purpose>Development of a Base Level Engineering (BLE) 2D hydraulic model to provide water-surface elevations and to characterize both pluvial and fluvial hazards contributing to increasing coverage of more comprehensive and graduated hazard identification products.</purpose>
    </descript>
    <timeperd>
      <timeinfo>
        <sngdate>
          <caldate>20240930</caldate>
        </sngdate>
      </timeinfo>
      <current>MIP Submission Date</current>
    </timeperd>
    <status>
      <progress>In work</progress>
      <update>Unknown</update>
    </status>
    <spdom>
      <bounding>
        <westbc>-95.992</westbc>
        <eastbc>-95.197</eastbc>
        <northbc>42.877</northbc>
        <southbc>41.989</southbc>
      </bounding>
    </spdom>
    <keywords>
      <theme>
        <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>hydrology</themekey>
        <themekey>environment</themekey>
        <themekey>inlandWaters</themekey>
        <themekey>structure</themekey>
        <themekey>transportation</themekey>
        <themekey>elevation</themekey>
      </theme>
      <theme>
        <themekt>FEMA NFIP Topic Category</themekt>
        <themekey>FIRM</themekey>
        <themekey>FEMA Flood Hazard Zone</themekey>
        <themekey>FIRM Database</themekey>
        <themekey>Special Flood Hazard Area</themekey>
        <themekey>Flood Insurance Rate Map</themekey>
        <themekey>Riverine Flooding</themekey>
        <themekey>Coastal Flooding</themekey>
        <themekey>NFIP</themekey>
        <themekey>Base Flood Elevation</themekey>
        <themekey>SFHA</themekey>
        <themekey>Floodway</themekey>
      </theme>
      <place>
        <placekt>None</placekt>
        <placekey>REGION 07</placekey>
        <placekey>STATE IA</placekey>
        <placekey>FEMA-CID MH22IA</placekey>
        <placekey>COUNTY BUENA VISTA</placekey>
        <placekey>COUNTY-FIPS 19021</placekey>
        <placekey>COUNTY WOODBURY</placekey>
        <placekey>COUNTY-FIPS 19193</placekey>
        <placekey>COUNTY CRAWFORD</placekey>
        <placekey>COUNTY-FIPS 19047</placekey>
        <placekey>COUNTY SAC</placekey>
        <placekey>COUNTY-FIPS 19161</placekey>
        <placekey>COUNTY IDA</placekey>
        <placekey>COUNTY-FIPS 19093</placekey>
        <placekey>COUNTY CHEROKEE</placekey>
        <placekey>COUNTY-FIPS 19035</placekey>
        <placekey>COUNTY MONONA</placekey>
        <placekey>COUNTY-FIPS 19133</placekey>
        <placekey>COMMUNITY ALTA, CITY OF</placekey>
        <placekey>BUENA VISTA COUNTY UNINCORPORATED AREAS</placekey>
        <placekey>COMMUNITY AURELIA, CITY OF</placekey>
        <placekey>CHEROKEE COUNTY UNINCORPORATED AREAS</placekey>
        <placekey>CRAWFORD COUNTY UNINCORPORATED AREAS</placekey>
        <placekey>COMMUNITY IDA GROVE, CITY OF</placekey>
        <placekey>COMMUNITY BATTLE CREEK, CITY OF</placekey>
        <placekey>COMMUNITY GALVA, CITY OF</placekey>
        <placekey>COMMUNITY HOLSTEIN, CITY OF</placekey>
        <placekey>COMMUNITY ARTHUR, CITY OF</placekey>
        <placekey>IDA COUNTY UNINCORPORATED AREAS</placekey>
        <placekey>COMMUNITY MAPLETON, CITY OF</placekey>
        <placekey>COMMUNITY CASTANA, CITY OF</placekey>
        <placekey>MONONA COUNTY UNINCORPORATED AREAS</placekey>
        <placekey>COMMUNITY TURIN, CITY OF</placekey>
        <placekey>COMMUNITY ODEBOLT, CITY OF</placekey>
        <placekey>COMMUNITY SCHALLER, CITY OF</placekey>
        <placekey>SAC COUNTY UNINCORPORATED AREAS</placekey>
        <placekey>COMMUNITY DANBURY, CITY OF</placekey>
        <placekey>WOODBURY COUNTY UNINCORPORATED AREAS</placekey>
        <placekey>FEMA-CID 190545</placekey>
        <placekey>FEMA-CID 190849</placekey>
        <placekey>FEMA-CID 190549</placekey>
        <placekey>FEMA-CID 190854</placekey>
        <placekey>FEMA-CID 190091</placekey>
        <placekey>FEMA-CID 190156</placekey>
        <placekey>FEMA-CID 190423</placekey>
        <placekey>FEMA-CID 190424</placekey>
        <placekey>FEMA-CID 190593</placekey>
        <placekey>FEMA-CID 190696</placekey>
        <placekey>FEMA-CID 190877</placekey>
        <placekey>FEMA-CID 190208</placekey>
        <placekey>FEMA-CID 190462</placekey>
        <placekey>FEMA-CID 190893</placekey>
        <placekey>FEMA-CID 190951</placekey>
        <placekey>FEMA-CID 190633</placekey>
        <placekey>FEMA-CID 190652</placekey>
        <placekey>FEMA-CID 190904</placekey>
        <placekey>FEMA-CID 190290</placekey>
        <placekey>FEMA-CID 190536</placekey>
      </place>
    </keywords>
    <accconst>None</accconst>
    <useconst>The hardcopy FIRM and FIRM Database and the accompanying FIS are the official designation of SFHAs and Base Flood Elevations (BFEs) for the NFIP. For the purposes of the NFIP, changes to the flood risk information published by FEMA may only be performed by FEMA and through the mechanisms established in the NFIP regulations (44 CFR Parts 59-78). These digital data are produced in conjunction with the hardcopy FIRMs and generally match the hardcopy map exactly. Acknowledgement of FEMA would be appreciated in products derived from these data.</useconst>
    <ptcontac>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>Federal Emergency Management Agency</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing</addrtype>
          <address>500 C Street, S.W.</address>
          <city>Washington</city>
          <state>District of Columbia</state>
          <postal>20472</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>1-877-336-2627</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>fema-riskmap-ithelp@fema.dhs.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </ptcontac>
    <native>Original data development environment may vary. Finishing of the data is done using Esri's ArcGIS software.The submitted geodatabase was created using ArcGIS version 10.5</native>
    <crossref>
      <citeinfo>
        <origin>AtkinsRealis</origin>
        <pubdate>20240930</pubdate>
        <title>BLE Area 3 MO-Little Sioux, Iowa FY22 DISC-BLE</title>
        <geoform>map</geoform>
        <pubinfo>
          <pubplace>Washington, DC</pubplace>
          <publish>Federal Emergency Management Agency</publish>
        </pubinfo>
        <onlink>https://msc.fema.gov</onlink>
      </citeinfo>
    </crossref>
  </idinfo>
  <dataqual>
    <attracc>
      <attraccr>Hydraulic analysis uses all valid existing flood elevation, survey, hydrologic analysis results, and other pertinent information for the study area. FEMA approved models are used to compute water surface elevations for required flood events. Computed water surface elevations and topographic data are used to delineate flood hazard boundaries. Roughness coefficients are carefully selected to represent the conditions along stream beds and banks. Hydraulics Data Capture submittals match the model output with respect to floodplain boundaries, cross sections, and water surface elevations and their precision. Floodplain boundaries and cross sections are not cartographically modified, and the data may not necessarily agree exactly with the published regulatory FIRM, FIRM Database, flood profiles, and Floodway Data Tables.</attraccr>
    </attracc>
    <logic>When FEMA revises an FIS, adjacent studies are checked to ensure agreement between flood elevations at the boundaries. Likewise, flood elevations at the confluence of streams studied independently are checked to ensure agreement at the confluence. The FIRM and the FIS are developed together and care is taken to ensure that the elevations and other features shown on the flood profiles in the FIS agree with the information shown on the FIRM. However, the elevations as shown on the FIRM may represent rounded whole-foot elevations. They must be shown so that a profile recreated from the elevations on the FIRM will match the FIS profiles within one half of one foot.</logic>
    <complete>Hydraulic analysis provides water surface elevations at different locations along the stream and for different flooding events. Hydraulic submittal includes key physical data used in the process, model parameters and model output. Data developed in surveying and hydrologic analysis are incorporated in hydraulic analysis. Results of hydraulic analysis are used to map Special Flood Hazard Area (SFHA) boundaries. Selection of model parameters (e.g., roughness coefficients, expansion and contraction coefficients, etc) is supported by additional information (e.g., landuse, aerial photo, etc). Model boundary conditions are carefully selected and justified. Modeled velocities are checked for potential erosion.</complete>
    <posacc>
      <horizpa>
        <horizpar>The FIRM Database consists of vector files and associated attributes produced in conjunction with the hardcopy FEMA FIRM. The published effective FIRM and FIRM Database are issued as the official designation of the SFHAs. As such they are adopted by local communities and form the basis for administration of the NFIP. For these purposes they are authoritative. Provisions exist in the regulations for public review, appeals and corrections of the flood risk information shown to better match real world conditions. As with any engineering analysis of this type, variation from the estimated flood heights and floodplain boundaries is possible. Details of FEMA's requirements for the FIS and flood mapping process that produces these data are available in the Guidelines and Standards for Flood Risk Analysis and Mapping. Horizontal accuracy was tested by manual comparison of source graphics with hardcopy plots and a symbolized display on an interactive computer graphic system. Independent quality control testing of the FIRM Database was also performed.</horizpar>
      </horizpa>
      <vertacc>
        <vertaccr>The FIRM Database consists of vector files and associated attributes produced in conjunction with the hardcopy FEMA FIRM. The published effective FIRM and FIRM Database are issued as the official designation of the SFHAs. As such they are adopted by local communities and form the basis for administration of the NFIP. For these purposes they are authoritative. Provisions exist in the regulations for public review, appeals and corrections of the flood risk information shown to better match real world conditions. As with any engineering analysis of this type, variation from the estimated flood heights and floodplain boundaries is possible. Details of FEMA's requirements for the FISs and flood mapping process that produces these data are available in the Guidelines and Standards for Flood Risk Analysis and Mapping. Vertical accuracy was tested by manual comparison of source graphics with hardcopy plots and a symbolized display on an interactive computer graphic system. Independent quality control testing of the FIRM database was also performed.</vertaccr>
      </vertacc>
    </posacc>
    <lineage>
      <srcinfo>
        <srccite>
          <citeinfo>
            <origin>AtkinsRealis</origin>
            <pubdate>20240930</pubdate>
            <title>BLE Area 3 MO-Little Sioux, Iowa FY22 DISC-BLE</title>
            <geoform>map</geoform>
            <pubinfo>
              <pubplace>Calverton, MD</pubplace>
              <publish>Federal Emergency Management Agency</publish>
            </pubinfo>
            <othercit>Effective FIS and FIRM from State of Iowa</othercit>
          </citeinfo>
        </srccite>
        <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
        <typesrc>Digital</typesrc>
        <srctime>
          <timeinfo>
            <sngdate>
              <caldate>20240930</caldate>
            </sngdate>
          </timeinfo>
          <srccurr>Publication date</srccurr>
        </srctime>
        <srccitea>STUDY29</srccitea>
        <srccontr>S_BFE, S_FLD_HAZ_AR, S_FLD_HAZ_LN, S_Hydro_Reach, S_Nodes, S_PROFIL_BASLN, S_Subbasins, S_Submittal_Info</srccontr>
      </srcinfo>
      <procstep>
        <procdesc>The FIRM Database is compiled in conjunction with the hardcopy FIRM and the final FIS report. The specifics of the hydrologic and hydraulic analyses performed are detailed in the FIS report. The results of these studies are submitted in digital format to FEMA. These data and unrevised data from effective FIRMs are compiled onto the base map used for FIRM publication and checked for accuracy and compliance with FEMA standards.</procdesc>
        <procdate>20240930</procdate>
      </procstep>
    </lineage>
  </dataqual>
  <spref>
    <horizsys>
      <planar>
        <gridsys>
          <gridsysn>State Plane Coordinate System 1983</gridsysn>
          <spcs>
            <spcszone>1401</spcszone>
            <lambertc>
              <stdparll>43.2666666666667</stdparll>
              <longcm>-93.5</longcm>
              <latprjo>41.5</latprjo>
              <feast>4921250</feast>
              <fnorth>3280833.3333</fnorth>
            </lambertc>
          </spcs>
        </gridsys>
        <planci>
          <plance>coordinate pair</plance>
          <coordrep>
            <absres>0.0025</absres>
            <ordres>0.0025</ordres>
          </coordrep>
          <plandu>survey feet</plandu>
        </planci>
      </planar>
      <geodetic>
        <horizdn>North American Datum of 1983</horizdn>
        <ellips>Geodetic Reference System 80</ellips>
        <semiaxis>6378137</semiaxis>
        <denflat>298.257222101</denflat>
      </geodetic>
    </horizsys>
    <vertdef>
      <altsys>
        <altdatum>North American Vertical Datum of 1988</altdatum>
        <altres>0.0001000000</altres>
        <altunits>Foot</altunits>
        <altenc>Implicit coordinate</altenc>
      </altsys>
    </vertdef>
  </spref>
  <eainfo>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>S_BFE</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Location and attributes for base flood elevation lines shown on the FIRM.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>FEMA FIRM Database Technical Reference (available at https://www.fema.gov/guidelines-and-standards-flood-risk-analysis-and-mapping and on the FEMA Risk MAP Knowledge Sharing Site).</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
    </detailed>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>S_Fld_Haz_Ar</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Location and attributes flood risk zones shown on the FIRM.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>FEMA FIRM Database Technical Reference (available at https://www.fema.gov/guidelines-and-standards-flood-risk-analysis-and-mapping and on the FEMA Risk MAP Knowledge Sharing Site).</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
    </detailed>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>S_Fld_Haz_Ln</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Location and attributes for boundaries of flood risk zones shown on the FIRM.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>FEMA FIRM Database Technical Reference (available at https://www.fema.gov/guidelines-and-standards-flood-risk-analysis-and-mapping and on the FEMA Risk MAP Knowledge Sharing Site).</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
    </detailed>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>S_Submittal_Info</enttypl>
        <enttypd>A spatial dataset consisting of polygons depicting the extents of the studied area.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>FEMA FIRM Database Technical Reference (available at https://www.fema.gov/guidelines-and-standards-flood-risk-analysis-and-mapping and on the FEMA Risk MAP Knowledge Sharing Site).</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
    </detailed>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>S_Hydro_Reach</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Location and attributes for lines that represent the connectivity between the subbasins and flow direction between nodes within the study area.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>FEMA FIRM Database Technical Reference (available at https://www.fema.gov/guidelines-and-standards-flood-risk-analysis-and-mapping and on the FEMA Risk MAP Knowledge Sharing Site).</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
    </detailed>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>S_Nodes</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Location and attributes of points that depict locations of computed discharges for the 10-, 4-, 2-, 1-, and 0.2-percent-annual-chance floods.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>FEMA FIRM Database Technical Reference (available at https://www.fema.gov/guidelines-and-standards-flood-risk-analysis-and-mapping and on the FEMA Risk MAP Knowledge Sharing Site).</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
    </detailed>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>S_Pol_Ar</enttypl>
        <enttypd>Location and attributes for political jurisdictions shown on the FIRM.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>FEMA FIRM Database Technical Reference (available at https://www.fema.gov/guidelines-and-standards-flood-risk-analysis-and-mapping and on the FEMA Risk MAP Knowledge Sharing Site).</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
    </detailed>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>S_Profil_Basln</enttypl>
        <enttypd>A spatial dataset consisting of lines showing the flow path used for floodplain modeling and mapping.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>FEMA FIRM Database Technical Reference (available at https://www.fema.gov/guidelines-and-standards-flood-risk-analysis-and-mapping and on the FEMA Risk MAP Knowledge Sharing Site).</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
    </detailed>
    <detailed>
      <enttyp>
        <enttypl>S_Subbasins</enttypl>
        <enttypd>A spatial dataset consisting of polygons representing watershed or subwatershed areas contributing runoff to the discharge points used in the hydrologic analysis.</enttypd>
        <enttypds>FEMA FIRM Database Technical Reference (available at https://www.fema.gov/guidelines-and-standards-flood-risk-analysis-and-mapping and on the FEMA Risk MAP Knowledge Sharing Site).</enttypds>
      </enttyp>
    </detailed>
    <overview>
      <eaover>The FIRM Database is made up of several data themes containing both spatial and attribute information. These data together represent the current flood risk for the subject area as identified by FEMA. The attribute tables include SFHA locations, flood zone designations, BFEs, political entities, cross-section locations, FIRM panel information, and other data related to the NFIP.</eaover>
      <eadetcit>FEMA's FIRM Database Technical Reference contains a detailed description of each attribute code and a reference to other relevant information.</eadetcit>
      <eadetcit>The following tables are included in this data set: L_Source_Cit S_BFE S_Fld_Haz_Ar S_Fld_Haz_Ln S_Submittal_Info</eadetcit>
    </overview>
  </eainfo>
  <distinfo>
    <distrib>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntorgp>
          <cntorg>FEMA, Flood Map Service Center</cntorg>
        </cntorgp>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing</addrtype>
          <address>P.O. Box 3617</address>
          <city>Oakton</city>
          <state>Virginia</state>
          <postal>22124</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>1-877-336-2627</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>fema-riskmap-ithelp@fema.dhs.gov</cntemail>
        <cntinst>Data requests must include the full name of the community or county and the FIRM panel number(s) covered by the request.</cntinst>
      </cntinfo>
    </distrib>
    <distliab>No warranty expressed or implied is made by FEMA regarding the utility of the data on any other system nor shall the act of distribution constitute any such warranty.</distliab>
    <stdorder>
      <digform>
        <digtinfo>
          <formname>Esri Shapefile</formname>
        </digtinfo>
        <digtopt>
          <onlinopt>
            <computer>
              <networka>
                <networkr>https://msc.fema.gov</networkr>
              </networka>
            </computer>
          </onlinopt>
        </digtopt>
      </digform>
      <fees>Contact Distributor</fees>
    </stdorder>
  </distinfo>
  <metainfo>
    <metd>20240930</metd>
    <metc>
      <cntinfo>
        <cntperp>
          <cntper>MIPHelp</cntper>
          <cntorg>Federal Emergency Management Agency</cntorg>
        </cntperp>
        <cntpos>Federal Insurance and Mitigation Administration</cntpos>
        <cntaddr>
          <addrtype>mailing</addrtype>
          <address>500 C Street, S.W.</address>
          <city>Washington</city>
          <state>District of Columbia</state>
          <postal>20472</postal>
          <country>USA</country>
        </cntaddr>
        <cntvoice>1-877-336-2627</cntvoice>
        <cntemail>fema-riskmap-ithelp@fema.dhs.gov</cntemail>
      </cntinfo>
    </metc>
    <metstdn>FGDC Content Standards for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
    <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
    <metextns>
      <onlink>https://hazards.fema.gov</onlink>
      <onlink>https://www.epsg.org</onlink>
      <metprof>FEMA NFIP Metadata Content and Format Standard</metprof>
    </metextns>
  </metainfo>
</metadata>
